We are all aware of the damaging pollution that’s created by driving petrol and diesel vehicles.
我们都清楚，驾驶汽油车和柴油车会产生有害污染。
Many of the world’s cities are clogged with traffic, creating fumes containing gases such as nitrogen oxides.
世界上许多城市都被交通拥堵所困扰，车辆排放的尾气中含有氮氧化物等气体。
The solution for a cleaner, greener future could be electric vehicles.
想要实现更清洁、更环保的未来，电动汽车或许是一个解决方案。
But how optimistic should we be?
但我们对此应该持多乐观的态度呢？
There was much excitement last year when the UK government announced it will ban the sale of new petrol and diesel cars from 2030.
去年英国政府宣布将从2030年起禁止销售新的汽油车和柴油车时，人们都感到十分振奋。
But is that easier said than done?
但这件事真的是说起来容易做起来难吗？
The road to global traffic being totally electric is still a long way off.
要实现全球交通全面电动化，还有很长的路要走。
Currently, battery life is an issue – a fully charged battery won’t take you as far as a full tank of petrol.
目前，电池续航能力是一大问题——一块充满电的电池，续航里程远不及一箱汽油。
There are also limited numbers of charging points to plug an EV into.
此外，可供电动汽车充电的充电桩数量也十分有限。
Of course, technology is always improving.
当然，技术一直在不断进步。
Some of the biggest tech companies, like Google and Tesla, are spending huge amounts of money developing electric cars. And most of the big car manufacturers are now making them too.
谷歌、特斯拉等大型科技公司都在投入巨资研发电动汽车，大多数主流汽车制造商如今也开始生产电动汽车。
Colin Herron, a consultant on low-carbon vehicle technology, told the BBC: “The big leap forward will come with solid state batteries, which will appear first in mobile phones and laptops before they progress to cars.”
低碳汽车技术顾问科林·赫伦在接受BBC采访时表示：“固态电池的出现将会带来巨大的技术飞跃，这类电池会率先应用于手机和笔记本电脑，之后才会推广到汽车领域。”
These will charge more quickly and give cars a bigger range.
固态电池充电速度更快，还能为汽车带来更长的续航里程。
Cost is another issue that may deter people switching to electric power.
成本是另一个可能阻碍人们转向电动汽车的因素。
But some countries offer incentives, such as cutting prices by reducing import taxes, and not charging for road tax and parking.
但一些国家推出了激励政策，比如通过降低进口税来压低车价，免除车辆的道路税和停车费。
Some also provide exclusive lanes for electric cars to be driven on, overtaking traditional cars which might be stuck in jams.
部分国家还专门设置了电动汽车专用车道，让电动汽车可以超越那些可能陷入拥堵的传统燃油车。
These kinds of measures have made Norway the country with the most electric cars per capita at more than thirty electric cars per 1000 inhabitants.
这类政策让挪威成为了人均电动汽车拥有量最高的国家，每1000名居民所拥有的电动汽车数量超过30辆。
But Colin Herron warns that ‘electric motoring’ doesn’t mean a zero-carbon future.
但科林·赫伦提醒道，“电动汽车出行”并不意味着零碳未来。
“It’s emission-free motoring, but the car has to be built, the battery has to be built, and the electricity does come from somewhere.”
“电动汽车行驶时确实不会产生尾气排放，但汽车本身需要制造，电池也需要生产，而且电力也并非凭空而来。”
Maybe it’s time to think about making fewer journeys or using public transport.
或许我们是时候考虑减少出行次数，或是多使用公共交通工具了。